Guide to the Alfred Schütz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files and Correspondence, 1927-1979; Series III; 6; (14 boxes)
  - Voegelin, Eric
    - "Der autoritäre Staatsfern," printed version, Wiener Zeitung, 1934 Apr 27
      See: Oversize, Box 35, folder 935a
    - "Bakunin's Confession," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 853)
    - "Befassungsgeburg für Österreich, printed version, Wiener Zeitung, 1934 May 13 (Box 31, Folder 853)
    - "Die ergänzende Bill zum Federal-Reserve-Act," offprint from Nationalwirtschaft (Box 31, Folder 854)
    - "La Follette und die Wisconsin-Idee," printed version, Zeitschrift für Politik, 1927 (Box 31, Folder 855)
    - "Kapitel: Einheit und Mannigfaltigkeit der menschlichen Art," typescript carbon (Box 31, Folder 856)
    - Mimeograph notes on Chinese history, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 857)
    - Mimeograph outlines of Japanese history, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 858)
    - "The Mongol Orders of Submission to European Powers, 1245-1255," offprint from Byzantion, 1940-41 (Box 32, Folder 859)
    - "More's Utopia," offprint from Osterr. Zeitschrift für öffentliches recht, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 860)
    - "The Nature of Law," mimeograph for law course, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 861)
    - "Neues Kammersystem im Spiegel der Geschichte," printed version, unidentified newspaper, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 862)
    - "Nietzsche and Pascal," typescript carbon (Box 32, Folder 863)
    - "Nietzsche, the Crisis and the War," galley proof, corrected (Box 32, Folder 864)
    - "The Origins of Totalitarianism," offprint from The Review of Politics, 1953 Jan (Box 32, Folder 865)
    - "Phänomenologie und Kulturwissenschaft," typescript carbon, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 866)
    - "Political Theory and the Pattern of General History," printed version, Research in Political Theory: A Symposium, 1944 Aug (Box 32, Folder 867)
    - "Rasse und Staat," offprint from Psychologie des Gemeinschaftlebens, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 868)
    - "Le régime administratif. Avantages et inconvénients," (with M. Adolf Merkl), offprint from Mémoires de l'académie internationale de droit comparé, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 869)
    - Review of Marvin Farber's The Foundation of Phenomenology, typescript carbon, [1943?] (Box 32, Folder 870)
    - Review of Frederick L. Schuman's Soviet Politics. At Home and Abroad, typescript carbon, [1946] (Box 32, Folder 871)
    - "Revolutionary Existence: Bakunin" Chapters 1, 3 and 4, typescript, corrected (Box 32, Folder 872)
    - "Studien zur Theorie des Bewusstseins," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 873)
    - "The Symbolization of Order," mimeograph, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 874)
    - "Theory of Legal Science: A Review," offprint from Louisiana Law Review, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 875)
    - Unidentified fragment: on absolute space and relativity, typescript carbon (Box 32, Folder 876)
    - Unidentified fragment: on economic systems, typescript carbon with note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 877)
    - Unidentified fragment: on law and liberty (Part Two: The History of Liberty and the Political Ideal of the Supremacy of the Law), mimeograph (Box 32, Folder 878)
    - Unidentified fragment: on the genesis of the Marxian idea, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 879)
    - Unidentified fragment: on Marx, typescript corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 880)
    - Unidentified foreword, with carbon copy of letter from Thomas Mann, 1938 Dec 18 (Box 32, Folder 881)
  - Von Mises, Ludwig
    - Correspondence, 1940, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 882)
    - Mimeograph exchange of Correspondence to Lionel Robbins, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 883)
    - Letter of recommendation for Alfred Schütz, 1947 Mar 10 (Box 33, Folder 884)
    - "Begreisen und Berstehen," offprint from Schmollers Jahrbuch, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 885)
    - "Bemerkungen über die mathematische Behandlung nationalökonomischer Probleme," offprint from Studium General, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 886)
    - "An Eastern Democratic Union," mimeograph, 1941 Jul 1 (Box 33, Folder 887)
    - "Economics as a Bridge for Interhuman Understanding," (prepared for the Sixth Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion), mimeograph (Box 33, Folder 888)
    - "'Elastic Expectations' and the Austrian Theory of the Trade Cycle," offprint from Economica, 1943 Aug (Box 33, Folder 889)
    - Review of On Freedom and Free Enterprise: Essays in Honour of Ludwig von Mises, clipping from The Economist, 1956 Sep 22 (Box 33, Folder 890)
  - Von Mises, Margit
    - Speech delivered at Hillsdale College, mimeograph, [1976?] (Box 33, Folder 891)
  - Wagner, Helmut
    - Correspondence, 1951-58 (Box 33, Folder 892)
    - Letters of recommendation for Alfred Schütz, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 893)
  - Waal, Elizabeth de
    - Correspondence, 1939 Feb 4 (Box 33, Folder 894)
  - Wahl, Jean
    - Correspondence, 1943-57 (Box 33, Folder 895)
  - Walters, M
    - Correspondence, 1954 Oct 24 (Box 33, Folder 896)
  - Weber, Marianne
    - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 33, Folder 897)
    - "Max Weber," offprint from Sozialwissenschaftliche Bausteine, 1932 (Box 33, Folder 898)
  - Weber, Max
    - Clipping, annotated, 1955 Aug 27 (Box 33, Folder 899)
  - Weichel, Neal
    - Correspondence, 1957 Mar 2 (Box 33, Folder 900)
  - Weisskopf, Walter A.
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 901)
  - White, David M.
    - Correspondence, 1959 Feb (Box 33, Folder 902)
  - White, Howard
    - Correspondence, 1941-58 (Box 33, Folder 903)
  - Williams, Richard Hays
    - Correspondence, 1940-41 (Box 33, Folder 904)
  - Wilson, Logan
    - Correspondence, 1947 Jun 18 (Box 33, Folder 905)
  - Winternitz, Emanuel
    - Poem "Mit einem Hyazinth" holograph and typescript with fragment of music, 1927, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 906)
  - Wood, Margaret Mary
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 907)
  - Wunderlich, Frieda
    - Correspondence, 1952, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 908)
  - Yale Review
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 909)
  - Wolff, Konrad
    - "Edmund Husserl 1.1.1934." typescript (Box 33, Folder 910)
  - Wolff, Kurt
    - Correspondence, 1945-59 (Box 33, Folder 911-913)
      Includes story by Wolff, "Surrender and Catch," typescript carbon and essay by Wolff, "Before and After Sociology," typescript carbon
    - Letter to Ilse Schütz, 1959 Sep 24 (Box 33, Folder 914)
    - Letter to Alfred Schütz Memorial Fund, 1961 Nov 30 (Box 33, Folder 915)
  - Unidentified
    - Letters to and from Alfred Schütz, 1940-44, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 916)
    - Letter to "Liebe Gnaedige Frau", 1939 May 25 (Box 33, Folder 917)
    - Letter to Ilse Schütz, 1956 Dec 2 (Box 33, Folder 918)
    - "An Approach of the Analysis of the Role of Rationality in Social Action," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 919)
    - "Diskussionsbemerkungen...Royaumont," holograph with "Alfred Schütz: Beantwortung der Diskussionsbemerkungen," holograph carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 920)
    - Notes on the International Social Science Journal, Vol. XII, No. 4, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 921)
    - "Recent Trends in West Germany's Balance of Payments," printed version, Monthly Review of Credit and Business Conditions, 1953 Dec (Box 33, Folder 922)
    - Untitled abstract: on the "home-comer" and the "home group," typescript carbon (Box 33, Folder 923)
    - Unidentified errata lists, holograph, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 924)
- Personal Papers, 1935-1959; Series IV; 0.25; (1 box)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, National Register - The Humanities and the Social Sciences, application, 1952 Apr 2 (Box 34, Folder 925)
  - Announcements and programs for music recitals, 1935, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 926)
  - Application for extension of travel privileges from France for Ilse Schütz, 1939 Jun 23 (Box 34, Folder 927)
  - Invitations to lectures by Schütz, 1952, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 928)
  - Lists of names and addresses (Box 34, Folder 929)
  - Lists of Schütz's publications, 1942-59, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 930)
  - Notes from a meeting[?], n.d. (Box 34, Folder 931)
  - Obituary notice, 1959 May (Box 34, Folder 932)
  - Résumé fragments, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 933)
  - Visa application for Isle Schütz's mother (photocopies), n.d. (Box 34, Folder 934)
- Additions Since 2003, 2001-2002; Series V; 2.67; (4 boxes)
  - ANNOTATIONS IN ALFRED SCHUTZ'S LIBRARY
    - Electronic files, 2001-02 (Box 37, Folder 968)
      [Access available through Public Services: Disk#01]
    - Microfilm, [2002] (Box 37, Folder 969-980)
    - Microfilm, [2002] (Box 38, Folder 981-992)
    - Microfilm, [2002] (Box 39, Folder 993-1004)
    - Microfilm, [2002] (Box 40, Folder 1005-1012)
- Oversize, 1934; 1.75; (1 box)
  - "Befassungsgeburg für Österreich, printed version, Wiener Zeitung, 1934 May 13 (Box 35, Folder 935)
  - "Der autoritäre Staatsfern," printed version, Wiener Zeitung, 1934 Apr 27 (Box 35, Folder 935a)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.25; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult appropriate curator.
  - Box 12, folder 215 (Box 36, Folder 936)
  - Box 15, folder 289 (Box 36, Folder 937)
  - Box 15, folder 296 (Box 36, Folder 938)
  - Box 17, folder 330 (Box 36, Folder 939)
  - Box 19, folder 357 (Box 36, Folder 940)
  - Box 20, folder 434 (Box 36, Folder 941)
  - Box 21, folder 454 (Box 36, Folder 942)
  - Box 24, folder 515 (Box 36, Folder 943)
  - Box 24, folder 518 (Box 36, Folder 944)
  - Box 25, folder 537 (Box 36, Folder 945)
  - Box 25, folder 543 (Box 36, Folder 946)
  - Box 25, folder 556 (Box 36, Folder 947)
  - Box 26, folder 587 (Box 36, Folder 948)
  - Box 26, folder 590 (Box 36, Folder 949)
  - Box 26, folder 595 (Box 36, Folder 950)
  - Box 27, folder 631 (Box 36, Folder 951)
  - Box 28, folder 672 (Box 36, Folder 952)
  - Box 28, folder 673 (Box 36, Folder 953)
  - Box 28, folder 674 (Box 36, Folder 954)
  - Box 28, folder 675 (Box 36, Folder 955)
  - Box 28, folder 680 (Box 36, Folder 956)
  - Box 28, folder 681 (Box 36, Folder 957)
  - Box 28, folder 696 (Box 36, Folder 958)
  - Box 30, folder 778 (Box 36, Folder 959)
  - Box 30, folder 780 (Box 36, Folder 960)
  - Box 30, folder 796 (Box 36, Folder 961)
  - Box 31, folder 831 (Box 36, Folder 962)
  - Box 32, folder 864 (Box 36, Folder 963)
  - Box 33, folder 882 (Box 36, Folder 964)
  - Box 33, folder 910 (Box 36, Folder 965)
  - Box 37, folder 968 (Box 36, Folder 966)
  - Box 37, folder 968 (Box 36, Folder 967)